All right so without further ado today what I'm going to talk about is
a newer service that we brought to the measure platform called as your api
apps and in particular I'm going to focus on a lot of different scenarios which you can
use as your api apps when you're building web apps mobile apps as well as logic
apps so we're going to look at all these today I do want to remind everyone to please scan at the
end of the session and submit feedback would love to learn some of your impressions about this new
service that were bringing of course love feedback in terms of how we articulated how we
presented and those sorts of things that helps the...teachers quite a bit.
I see okay so today here's the
...ways...going to walk through so we're going to talk about some of the challenges
that you've told us that you face when
authoring as well as consuming apis we're going to talk a little bit about the architecture
of api apps...and spend time focus authentication we'll look at all
...different languages and tools and decays that you can use in order to interact with the
measure api apps we're going to try to talk to some on premises services as well we'll give
...a try and, then of course we've got sas connectors and are going to look at logic apps
...so a whole bunch of different things in fact what this I think
...to reinforces that these as your api apps
of foundational piece of some of the app services technology that live within,
within manager now the last couple of days I've spent a lot of time at the booth I probably spoken do a lot of you
and even in the weeks before the conference we spent a lot of time talking to developers
about some of the challenges faced when interacting with apis and here's just
and enumeration of some of these all the manual plumbing that you end up having to
write when building out new apis whether deals with logging or authentication or
single sign on interacting with secret stores or configuration
and a lot heard a lot about versioning and updating of the apis as well?
Integrating into on premises services is a key need felt by a lot of people
...on that as well today so that was one of the difficulties
as well in terms of authoring api apps being able to connect to the
data that you have in the enterprise that does not live within the cloud.
As well as connecting to sas investments whether that's office three sixty five or sales
force drop box or some other api that you end up consuming is part of your
enterprise governance and monitoring of apis understanding how people are using your apis
and having control over it as well as just some of the complexity around the existing
...are making making providing
some impedance and preventing you from being able to connect to these apis.
Is anyone fuel or which agree with some of these challenges
...I'm seeing a lot of nodding heads I heard some yeses so now on the other side when it comes
to consuming apis yet again a lot of feedback that we received you know,
we all-consuming we all author apis but that's not to say it isn't difficult and
then it couldn't be made easier and as you start looking at providing apis to support
the business and support your customers and your companies
that's almost next to impossible to expose some of these apis in a way that makes
it consumable for them...all over-the-board when it comes to metadata in how we
describer apis as well as authentication
and over we hear about this lack of being able to scope apis
...organizational level being able to describe a set of apis that are important to this
organization versus another one to another organization and of course at the end and I don't know that
we'll solve this today but always a lack of
good api documentation so this is one of the these issues that we enumerate
...these couple slides are some of the drivers for why we started looking at creating
we've called as your api apps so what as
...api apps aspires to be as a platform and ecosystem and I'll talk about that
...that makes it easier for you to build
and consuming distribute apis in the cloud and on premises so why
...your api apps and what is that were accomplishing so I actually standing in the hallway before
the talk I was speaking to a gentleman that asked me before the before hand,
you know, why as your api up's instead of just web apps, you know, what's the difference I think that's a very good
question and something that I want to spend a little time talking about here before we go any
further on the left side you're going to see a bunch of benefits that come with the as your app
servicesplatform so that includes web apps as well as api
apps being a part of that platform means that these services automatically get
and to take the advantage of things like automatic...a patching enterprise
grade security high availability in all the other things enumerated that list so
api apps in a sense is built on web apps and built on app of the
app service which means that it gets inherently all these advantages but there's a
few other things that come with api apps that we think bring value to
api app developers as well as consumers so these are some of the things listed on the right side
here so bring your api as it is...don't have to rewrite your api if
you're dot net developer in your authoring your api web api
...fantastic...work fantastically on as your api apps if you're writing and
go or node you can still use those apis the way that you've authored
them within measure api apps we're not asking you to change how you build your apis we
provide mechanisms for simpler access control and we're going to spend a lot of time looking at authentication
here connectivity to sas platforms having access to connectors which
...also show you and talk about here makes it easier for you to connect to the
sas services that you care about we've taken a hard look at
...different metadata formats and I have really started to pivot
around swagger I'm not sure if you're familiar with swagger it's a way of describing
rest apis and one of the things that asher api
abs does really well is helps you describe your apis with swagger
...becomes easier to use your apis elsewhere whether it's consuming it from your
web apps or interacting with it via logic apps as well?
We've got some very specific
...visual studio tooling support which I'll show you here shortly and we do have a
public marketplace today where you can go and get third-party
...first party being microsoft as
your api apps that already exist so you can very easily instantiate them and I'll show you that now I do
list private marketplace there as well and that is something that will be bringing in the future
...talk...the into the talk but the idea that you
can also create and then have in a private organizational gallery
the api apps that you care about verses having to make them public to the world?
Now to other things listed here which are also things that...bring the platform are just like
new get has a way of managing dependencies between libraries...
Some of the run times that you use also with as your api apps you
can describe dependencies across as your api apps as well so that if you're using it as
your api app within your custom as your api app you can
describe that dependency and when it gets
deployed in manage it will end up using that dependent measure api up
then the last thing which we think is really exciting as well is we use semantic versioning on the
as your api apps as a way to manage version and you can opt into having
measure api apps automatically updated when the
package is updated as well so these are a bunch of different things that we brought with as
your api apps that we think help to solve some of those challenges so
what I want to do is with that show...first demo of how you can build
in interact with these as your api apps I'm going to switch over here now I'm going to
start here at the new the been x the as report all I'm assuming most of
you have seen this by now and you know, there's the first-class experience for creating new as your
api app we can go new choose web plus mobile and you'll see there's a whole bunch of different you know,
apps available of course we care here about the api app now when you create
...api appI'll
...talk about the architecture here...little bits of reinforce some of these things but a
couple of different pieces of infrastructure actually get deployed the first-time and they're going to it's what's,
what's also important to be cognizant of is some of the choices you make one building
your api app so for instance here I can give it a name I can choose
a service plan now service plan for leisure api up is just the same concept
as it is with the web app when you choose your service plan you're actually choosing the infrastructure
that's hosting your api app so the actual machine the virtual machine so,
you can have multiple api apps deployed and running on the same infrastructure...
by choosing to by choosing the exact same service plan so here I could choose a service
...already exists of course pricing...and resource group which becomes
a logical container for the resources that I'm deploying and subscription and I can
deploy so I'm just going to go ahead and deploy that now what's happening when
I when I created is it's going to use the measure resource manager to
instantiating create some infrastructure it takes about a minute-and-a-half to create but
once they're in your resource group you'll have a gateway which we'll talk a little bit more
...as well as the api app now just for the sake of
time I have one already created and I haven't done anything to it and,
it right here it's called the face detection api apps I'm going to go ahead so like that and
...I open it up you'll see here the as your api
...blade and in this blade we have a bunch of information
pertinent to this api app I'm going to spend a little bit time talking about some of
it for instance if you look here you can see that I've got a couple things, you know,
some of the resource group that we showed before subscription but I also have this api
outpost and gateway now the api...host is the actual web app that
the api up is running on so-if you want-to get to the web
apt to do some certain to do different things like maybe
...continuous integration which I'll shown a moment...change
...way in which scales you can select the apa
post actually go to the underlying web app and make those changes similarly if you want to
make changes to the gateway which runs in its own web app post you can
selectively gateway there and start making changes to it I'm
...some time later talking a little bit more about things like api definition so what I want to do is
first just go to all settings and
to application settings and just talk a little bit here about what
...end up seeing so you seeup automatic updates so you can automatically in
list into updates for api apps but you can also specify access levels
so what and access level is controlling who can get access to your apis by
default there's three different levels or but there are three different axis levels there's
...to internal meaning that only other as
your api apps running in the resource group the same resource group can talk to this
api of this api app so by default...up with...constrained
access levels you can change that to public authenticated which means that you
cantalk to this api up from outside of the resource group
which you have to do so with some sort of authentication or you can make
it anonymous so for this first demo what I'm going to do is just simply make this public anonymous
...becomes very easy for us to talk to it...saved that change?
And, now our api post is ready to go there's no coding it yet so...going to do is switch
over to visual studio will start building the app that will deploy into it now the...I've
decided to build is I think a fairly representative app of the kind of things that
you'll use api outposts for in this case I'm going to talk to a third-party third parties
...provider by the name of alchemy api...going to use is there
a facial detection service so that I can submit the image to their service
...returns...information back they do
they determine the gender based on the picture they'll make a guess on
age and then also if they have a public repository of well-known
famous people and they'll actually scan that repository to see if the picture is someone famous or
with the likelihood is that they are that person so what's go ahead and build it now the first thing I'm going to do is actually
create a class now I'm going to do a multi part form post to this api so I'm just going
...first create a provider that can make it easier for me to keep this
image and memory this is particularly important for the demo
but it does it I do need in order for to work so let me go ahead and create this provider?
Because I can never type well I've got a couple snippets here to go ahead and get this
goin' so this is basically
it's multi-stream provider that's going to allow me to post the image to this web api
and then grab the streams that I can do something with the stream and what I'm going to do is pass
it to the alchemy api...so I'm going to come the controller and here we've got
the values controller...just go ahead and rename this to facial?
And, not going to use of these defaults but instead.
Let me add a couple different things.
The first things I'm going to add...just a couple keys so there's an api key that are used in order to access
as well as the url for alchemy and then.
Let's add the api itself so here I've got a method that's going to allow me to
post to it ...to check to see if it's a multi part post if not it's going to send back a message saying it's
about request and, then it's using that provider to
essentially down here take the information that was posted up to intern
...file stream another I have the file stream I can go ahead and.
Creating new http...posted...to url
check the status code and then essentially take the response and the serialized
...and then return it back so essentially
this is just really a wrapper around the alchemy api.
The alchemy apis...detection service so let's go ahead and give run
this and check it out and see it make sure that it's running locally.
So, actually one thing before I do that one thing to be aware of is I didn't really point this out
...forgot to apologies you'll notice that the project template for an api app
doesn't have everything you might see in, you know, traditional nbc or even a web
pr app so a lot of the views...lot of things have been removed because the assumption is that you're
going to be focusing on building your apis but they're actually are a couple of interesting things that have been added to this
as well probably the most important is by default we've got
that's really interesting we've got swashbuckling right here so you can see swashbuckling is a new get
package that's been added what swashbuckling is...it's a library in...set of?
And, some code that will interrogate the api that you build in
your api controllers and generate the swagger
for-you so it'll describe your api using swagger meta
data and we can demonstrate that pretty easily by coming in here to the swagger configured and
...little bit down here there's a whole bunch of commented but there's a piece of code here that's
...called enable swagger you
...so if we uncommon this and run.
You know, there is no home
controller or initial view but we can do now is types swagger
and a using with swashbuckling swagger what it's doing is creating a little
harness for me to interact with the api so I can take a look at it and, you know,
see the descriptions and in some cases very easily, you know, collar get or a
post against you can also then take this string here and
...that in and see the actual swagger
jason that describes the apis as well we'll talk more about this later because
it comes very important when it comes to how you interact with the api apps you build so,
I've got it running let's go to post man and we just grab the url here and
...man we're going to do is a posts...to the endpoints api slash
Detection is what I call that no facial detection.
And, I'm going to do is...a file.
And, I've got a couple files here so.
Here's a...I actually did this earlier to see if it
...detective as a famous person and we'll see what the results are.
So, what comes back is some
coherence you'll see it comes back we've got an age range predicted of thirty five to
forty four I assume that's somewhere in the ballpark male so pretty,
pretty, pretty strongly scores mail and it is not actually detect...as scott guthrie
so if it did it would return back some additional information describing you-know-who it thinks that
the person is interestingly enough I took a picture myself and,
let me go ahead and add that and I'll send it to the service?
And, it makes some interesting predictions let's see what the result is.
So, actually turns out so first of all age range eighteen twenty four which I'm okay with.
Male which is correct and it's interesting it fines in this repository
of public images a gentleman name mikhail coder...skier
...very well so I of course I had to take a look to see...this was and.
...you guys tell me.
They say everyone has a twins I must maybe I found my twin.
...right it's an interesting service there's a whole bunch of other stuff but kind of fun to play with but so
...running locally let's go ahead and see what we can do not to
...so I'm going to go to my project right click and say publish and...familiar with
this published dialogue web apps you can import custom etc and you'll notice that
we also have now as your api apps in preview so I'm going-to go ahead
so like this and it's going to take a look at my subscription and see if I have
any existing api apps and,
of course I do some...select the face detection api app now
you could also select new instead of going through the portal you can create your...api out from
bs I want-to make sure you guys...the portal experience so ones like that and it
sets it up just like web apps is going to use publish settings file and it's going to end up doing a
web deploying push that so it's just take a moment.
Visual...not responding this take a moment to deploy.
Since already running it should be very quick so publishes...
is succeeded and that's restarting the gateway now this is important if you end up making
changes and we're going to show us an area where we're going to use continuous integration to make changes
us you need to restart the gateway so that recognizes
the swagger metadata that's been a attached to it so if you ever change the swagger
need to make sure that gateway has been reset so I'm going to grab that url.
And, come back here to postman instead of posting locally that's go ahead and switch that to
my api app and we'll just go ahead well here I'll choose a different images time my
friend adam and I and will...send and we'll see now we're talking to
our publicly anonymous as your api app that we've got
...we should see...response coming back here momentarily?
And, there isthis time we got
information about both of us so that's a very simple look at you know,
first-ever api app built-in visual studio of created from the
portal ...it further in a moment but let me go ahead and come back here to the presentation.
So, I mentioned a bunch of this stuff already but just maybe
...mentioning again as your api apps built on web apps
but provides a bunch of additional capabilities as well makes it easy to do access control
iso the metadata contracts provided by swagger it is
micros service styleone of the things that we really felt inspired by from microsoft mrs was
the idea of single purpose apis and being able to...package
...apis in a way where they're focused on the purpose of api so that they're more compose
...so we believe that the way in which you create and packages measure apis helps
you to deliver on that micros service style of single purpose compose
...apis as well and I'm going to
...bit here on premises and some of the other publishing pieces so now
here is diagram to hopefully hope to make sense of what's actually
...happening underneath, underneath the scenes so when you employer measure api
at for the first-time into let's say a new resource group are two things will be
provisions one is the gateway so you see on the left side here there's an as
your at gateway and when you when you're communicating with your as your api
you're actually communicating to via this app gateway and
there's a number of reasons for it going back to the discussion around challenges for apis
and some of the things that we're trying to make easier without your api apps one of the things is providing a
token store so if you're communicating to a sas api that has you know,
...client secret or something that's used to authenticate to it rather than doing what I
did in the first demo which is I put it right into my as your api app you can actually pull that from a
secure token store this provided as part of the platform...available via the gateway?
The other thing that helps with this too isit takes advantage of a consent
server which will facilitate some of the things that are needed as part of communicating with sas
api such as refreshing tokens I'm storing the tokens as they come back so forth
so that consent server it helps to facilitate some of the interactions the
login interactions that might occur otherwise and we'll see this in effect in logic apps here
...now behind the gateway is all the additional things that are
...that you've deployed so all the api apps so, you can deploy one or more as
your api apps into a resource group all of which will then use that application gateway that as
your api gateway so in this example here you'll see that there's a bunch of connectors like
a sales force connector ...sixty-five connector tool
your connector these are as your api apps that are facilitating connections to
sas providers but then you can also deploy custom
...api apps just like the one that I wrote for the facial
recognition at the same time to there are logic apps...talk a little bit more about them later but,
hopefully this helps to just describe a little bit of how these things are organized
in some of the different resources that are now going a little bit and more detail when it comes
to the gateway there's a lot happening in the gateway and over time even more will be happening in
the gateway...is what manages a not only access levels so
you saw how we can set things to internal or public anonymous or public-private
public authenticated but it also helps to do things like
...resolution being able to resolve how you can communicate to other is your api
...that's where it's through the gateway that you get access to isolated storage and shared
configure and, one of the things I'll show you in the portal in a moment
is the kind of api logging that's also available to you via the gateway so
you can see you know-how many requests are coming in how
many failed one of the responses that have been being sent to so forth?
So, talking a little bit more...authentication hopefully the three levels of access makes
sense so public anonymous so anyone can access...public authenticated which I'll talk a little bit more
one moment and then internal again internal being only other as
your api apps being able to talk to it and I do mean only other as
...api apps you might expect a web app deployed in
side a resource group to be able to talk to an internal as your api...but that's not the case
we decided to when it is markers internal is only other as
your api apps that can communicate to it now public authenticated is
...work it's interesting because there's a lot of different ways that you might want
to facilitate access to your as your api app so there's a number of ways that we provide
today and overtime this will continue to grow.
The first...the most important is as...active directory and I'll show you how this functions in a moment
how we can set it up and then authentic and then the secure our as
your apis using adjective directory you can use...nsa or microsoft account
...live id as well as some social identity providers such as facebook google
on twitter.
So, I believe design...slide I apologize about that
...all screwed up here so this is what I just discussed now what I want to do is show how you
can add eighty support to your api apps.
So, I'll switch over so I'm going to do is the same map
that we just built that was set as a public anonymous we're going to set to
public-private and show how we can...such that we can communicate to it so we'll start often portal.
And, I'm going to go to the as your api up again and this time set the
app setting instead of being public anonymous...set to public authenticated and save
that so we've set the access level but we haven't actually define
what identity provider we want to use if you recall from the architecture slide we do that
on a gateway somebody go ahead and select the gateway which is right here in the
blade and then...set the...settings.
And, one of the things that you'll seewhen you...settings for the gateway is identity and
it will list out the identity providers that are available today now each one of the requires
a somewhat some configuration I found with customers the most questions with
...active directory so I'm going to demonstrate how we can use adjective directory to secure this
...now a couple things are provided for you when you select this including
app url and a reply url and this is important in setting up with your id piece
that, you know, how to facilitate the communication back and forth you also need to specify with the client id
is for the identity provider using and in the case of measure active directory we want to
specify which tenant which active directory tenant that we want to
allow access to so we're going to go ahead and do that I'm going to copy this ...app url
because I'm going to use it quite a bit here I'm going to flip over to the...current
portal management managed...dot windows measure dot com and that's because as
you're active directory only surfaces up-to-date in this portal so here are
selected active directory and I have a...here called
...wagner now this is actually...all of you that have an nsa or microsoft account
...you also have a ad
tenant in this case might this is automatically created for my m...it's called
...wagner gmail dot on microsoft-dot-com so you guys can take a look and, you
know, take a look at the that for yourself as well once I selected I can come here to applications that I'm going to create
and application specific to the surface that I'm
...services that I'm securing summers says application
...organizations developing call whatever call
it build demo and it's a web
...whether api...asking for the single sign on
...url and the api app...so in this case we're going to
...that first url that we got from the ep settings
page so that it points to essentially our gateway slash login slash
ad and save that it'll create the appnow there's a couple of the things that will need
to do what we're going to have to specify with the reply url is so that it knows where to
...as after we've authenticated some...to copy that reply url?
And, come to configure.
Instead of having it...reply
back to the login instead we're going to do is put the reply url
and here and...I'm actually going to also put in a http
go ahead and save this so now it knows where to send back and authenticated user.
And, I'm also going to grab this client id because I need to specify the client id in the
id p settings on the previous page...copy that
...id put in here and then specify my
allowed tenants so that is in this case
...wagner gmail dot on microsoft-dot-com.
And, save that.
So, at this point what we've done is we've...specify that are as
...api app is public authenticated and we've now configured
...id...so let's go ahead and try to give it a let's try to interact with it so,
actually first let me just go ahead and
...demonstrate that it's no longer underwater able to talk to...all go
ahead and,...request and I shouldn't getting back a failure message here and,
it could not authenticate to it.
Taking a little longer than I would...too.
So, I'm going-to go ahead and grab this log in url while we're waiting for that and see here the exception
is not the best I know we are still working on a sending back
appropriate responses when there's an error of this isn't preview still so but,
what I want to do is demonstrate pretty easily how I can now authenticate with
...and actually specify the gateway log in ...that's going to do is so,
I have a cookie issue let me go ahead and just reset my cookies?
So, one of the things that was going to talk about moment I'll explain now since I'm doing this is as
your api apps actually uses the same authentication technology that mobile apps
...mobile services you so using zero tokens zoom
...bt tokens are dots.
So, when the things that it does it will take a do more token and
put it in a cookie and I just had a still cookie that I had to remove so now I'm going
to go ahead and log in now this isn't going to be the same user that I log into
the portals since this is actually my ...wagner gmail tenant some
log in with waited at...wagner gmail dot on microsoft-dot-com so it's an actual
user in that tenant and go ahead and login?
...sign-in and.
Invalid zero header.
So, let me see if I can just delete this their.
Try that again.
...login complete fantastic all right so now what I'm
...is since it should have logged in hopefully...created actual so,
apology so again I what I needed to do is remove, remove a
stale cookie and, what's happened is now I've authenticated with the
eighty provider and its created a cookiethat I can
...using for authenticated now this is great...interactive web apps where
you've authenticated redirected back and now that cookies available can
...within your application you can also programmatic...get this token
using sdk and what it's going to get you is this token right here which is a...
token mcbride and copy this and ...that's not the full token let me try again?
There we go I've no idea why it takes so many copy
...this is the full token so this is what stored within the cookie so when we authenticate
...this token now what I'm going to do is just a demonstrate that I can authenticate now to this I'm
going to go open up post...and.
This time I'm going to attach a header to the call that I made before called x
dash zero.
...in that token select an image again and
send so now when I'm interacting with its passing in the token
and it will get through the gateway as a result and I'll be able to interact my api.
And, you can see the response comes back so apologies for the difficulties there but we got through it so thank you.
All right I appreciate that thank you.
All right so that's just one example of course there's a bunch
great tutorials and showing essays and facebook so forth but, we made it through
...so fantastic now a little bit more about languages so,
one of the nice things about being built on web apps is api apps can take advantage of
any languages supported by the as...web app and as
result you can end up writing your as your apis api apps in dot net
java php node and yes even go so I'm going to demonstrate here
...in fact I got some cool things are on that but I'll get...the
...we have first-class tooling support today in visual studio but one of the things coming
very soon I mean very soon is we're going to be adding as your api apps to the
cross platform cy tool which would be great ...you know,
if you're like me I actually don't always like having to go to the portal and clicking a whole bunch
...much rather right some scripts and run description of the things that I want...so very soon we'll have the
cross platforms...tool which can run not only on windows but it can run on
...as well as licks.
Now in terms of sdk is there is a new get package for dot net that
makes it easier for you to interact with things like isolated storage
and getting access to tokens and basically managing simplifying a lot of...for
you and we're going to be bringing more us decays over time as well for other languages but
in reality you can do anything and everything the http client everything's accessible the gateway
veer as your api apps so I'm using the documentation you can you can
pull from isolated storage from any language that you want to one thing I'm not going to demonstrate though
that is really neat is given the fact that we have swagger support for all
these api apps you can use tools like auto rests
to generate client libraries how many of you here heard of auto rest.
Few hands of take a look at it it's all open-source...upon get hub
there's a tool...that you can get through chocolate he you can also get through new get and what it
allows you to do is essentially run against a swagger jason file
it will generate class libraries that you can use for interacting with that rest api
...very handy very nice tool to use in addition to as your api apps?
So, what I want to demonstrate here real quick now is how we can do very much the same thing but we can do it with
go now one of the reasons that this works today isjust
...close my browser well you can take a look I just recently
theweb apps team that creates...do which is a technology that
manages a whole bunch of the management of web apps in terms...integration and
all sorts of different things are committed a bunch of code that will take go
...language files and actually compile...and host them so what that means
is I can now basically grab some go code so I'm going to actually grab go code that I have
up and get hub so let me go to the repository and there's a
...go where you can do a go get against a uri
...defines where the code is
going to grab this here and I can come into the command line say go get and
the project name and what that's going to do is grab all that code from
a get hub and then let's go into that folder?
And, you can see here here's the...code...spend a lot of time and here since
this isn't the point of the talk but you can see here is the main function and
it checks to see if there's a platform port because once running up and as your it has a different port...
would locally so on that thing I want to point out though is go does not have support
for...generating swagger to donald like dot net does with swashbuckling so one of the things that I
think valuable in this demo is we still can provide our swagger,
swagger meta data through a convention
and that convention is to create a metadata folder and that metadata folder
provide adjacent file called api...dot swagger not jason
if you look at that this is just swagger data that I created actually using the swagger dot io
...that describes my api and basically shows
a to do index and some other things so by putting this in this folder this means that when I go to
deploy disco app I'll still end up getting access to that swagger metadata which means that I can in
the then consuming...as your api very easily from different clients so in order to
write to get this to work what I'm going to do is go to the api
apt I have deployed for it and me
go ahead and select that one so I've got an api up that I'd
provision already calledgo to do api app and I
mention that this is running out a web app so as a result we can take advantage of all of the web...capability
so I'm going to go into the web app...and some of you're probably familiar with the ability to set up
continuous integration so if I slide down here to our deployment.
Once it loads I can selected and choose to enable a
local get repository so this becomes a great way in order to deploy a code into
our api app some choose the source...choose local get repository
click okay and what's going to do is set up on my api app api app
outpost...get repository they'll be able to commit code into now
it's created it if I selected what it's going to do...give me some
helpful urls here like the get url there is a bug here right now and I'll show you what that is
...remember this is preview...fix you can see here is actually sending the wrong name back this is not
by might deployment username so if I just switch this to
...wagner which is what it is the rest of this get uri here is correct...ahead and grab that
...right now that I fixed it and I'm going to initialize this folder and I'll
do get remote ad as your and I'll pasting that get
uri and now I can just ...my code I can
commits initial and get push measure master
and this is where a lot of cool stuff happens...site login is given the updates to
...do what it's going to do is it's going to discover that I'm committing a bunch of dot
go files and it's going to compile all those go files down into a binary
update the web dot configure using the http web what are the http platform handler
...that binary and then my api app is going to start actually
accepting requests and responses using this
go code so you can see all this is happening on my as...api up
...should take a moment to finish.
And, when it does we can end up calling into our go as your api app so there
is finished one thing I need to do is by default this is
set to internal so let's go ahead before I?
Failed is demo and switch this to.
To public anonymous.
All right.
And, then in post man actually no I don't even need postman for this I'm going-to go ahead and just
call directly to.
It says welcome not very cool but watch this is an api upright
...website so to dues there we go I get my jason back I can also
then say to do slash one so on so forth so you can see here you can
author using any language and then using continuous integration via get thirty
fs or whatever you might want...abusing in order to get your code into that as your api out.
Thanks.
connecting the on premises data this is something that we've been told is very critical to our customers
and there's a lot of there's actually a
number of different solutions for doing this today we have inside of web apps
...a something that's been around for a little while called hybrid connections so what hybrids
connections does it uses the service
...relay capabilities in order to establish a site a port
it basically establish a tcp connection to a port that you define on
your local machine so I can install some software here specify what the
port is and this define the service
...and once it comes online it'll then
facilitated point-to-pointconnection between a resource up in the cloud as well as
resource I have running locally this is fantastic for
developers it's also very good if you have something like sequel server
my sequel or something that runs on a machine and you don't want to expose the entire machine
to your resources running up in the cloud so it's very surgical
innocence you can be very specific in terms of what you want to open
up on premises at the same time we have a technology called virtual networks which provides a lot
of very strong enterprise capabilities for doing things such as establishing
...site or site the point
...we're opening up your network and actually actually exposing your
network and essentially allowing you to extend your network...your
resources in the cloud both of these are very goodvery good options I think earlier
...yo high give a talk on the app service
which they described the ability to establish these cite this site vp
...network virtual networks which was just enabled recently in the platform
is one of the announcements earlier this week so these are very good ways in which you
can try to connect to resources local now I'm going to attempt here
to give a demonstration with the caveat that earlier today
we did have some issues with the base...services enabling it so hopefully this
...up going falsely it's a fantastic demos I really hope it works?
But, the reason I'm going to still going through that knowing that it could actually fail
is I think it's valuable to least go through it and it's only the end part that may and failing
...you'll still see how you can do-it-yourself go ahead and create
a new project and I still going to be and api measure api app and
what I'm going to do in this measure api app is connect to a local database so well,
that's opening let-me open up the ...sequel server studio management studio?
And, I'm going to in the controller here go ahead and rename this and we're going to call this
a product products controller.
And, I can use any of this.
I'm going to use this instead so what you see here is code that I
think is very representative of a lot of the code that you know, you maybe writing others right
and I'm going to get some I get a product let me go ahead and create that product here real quick.
And, the product kind of product id a name and a price.
And, here.
...to do is I'm a select the top hundred products...did just want-to make sure mice
...my connection string is a secure but what you can see here
is if I run it locally it's going to talk to this database?
And, it's going to return back...this data so you can see there...now let's go ahead and run it.
...one thing I want to do first is we're going to use
the swagger you why in order to access it so let me go ahead and update
this setting here so that we turn on this wire ui.
Which was higher up in the file?
Yes, like at the top.
All right so.
That's going grab that...post man reset this.
And, api slash products.
send requests and you can see here I get product id one just...just a just a
...believed...edit this.
Edit top two hundred rows it's just change this price to five dollars.
Execute this again so you can
...the five all right so let's go ahead and deploy this.
Up into our api app which I prefer vision but I haven't done anything to it so as...api apps.
...deploy it to.
This one here on premises sales db api app...kind of a mouthful and
while this is publishing let's go back to the portal and this is where I'm hoping that the problems I had
earlier resolved what we want to do is go to the app post enable
the hybrid connection so all right so here's running.
...outlook.
And, believe this is the right api app yep
...the first thing first let's go ahead and just make sure that we
said this to public anonymous because it's easier that way for the demo.
And, now I'm going to go the app posts.
And, again, this app post blade here is really the same thing as a web app
...so if you slide down you'll note that we have hybrid connection
once that loads available as a tile.
So,...like hybrid connection now hybrid connections use biztalk
services and the service...relay in order to establish that connection so you'll see I don't have
any hybrid connections in this resource groups I'm going to add one and I'm going to create a new
...connection this will be called on premises sales
db and the host name as my computer name
and port so one of the things that you didn't see because I encoded
...string but it's communicating to my database using
tcp connection string goes to the server name
comma fourteen thirty three so if we established
a hybrid connection and if it's enabled and if it's if everything's flowing
then from the...I can still call to my machine...tcp port fourteen
thirty-three and it will be able to talk my database so in order to do this I need to use
the best...service and this is the part that may
...right now so let's see I will say this is also still in preview
so click...
So, let me describe what should happen so when you click
okay what it'll do is...create the biztalk service which essentially creates the service
...really in the background and allow you to create
...hybrid connection once you've created the hybrid connection you'll get another blade
they'll open up...let-you download and emma side that you can install which facilitates the
client-side connectivity to the service...relay when that's established this
light or you can't see it right now because it's I can't open up a existing every connection but
basically a light turns on saying that you're pipe is available and
when we deploy we should be able to run the same api up in the cloud using the same
connection string that we did locally in order to talk for database
it's a fantastic demo maybe sometime I'll get an opportunity to give it again so?
All right so how we doing on time
...a few minutes left so one of the things I'll talk about before
we're done is connectors so there's a lot of connectors that we made available when we
launched app service and api apps and you can see here everything
from chatter to drop box to measure media services are all available
...as connectors now these connectors are really nothing more than
...measure api apps that have been set up such that they make it very easy for you to
connect to these sas providers...they also do is facilitate a lot of different types of
protocol and protocol communications so you'll find adapters for connecting to
at via ftp...pop three so,
the...team that a lot of work in order to take these capabilities and bring them...connectors
and even some of the services that is talk services provides around,
you know,...validation and, you know, all the better
type operations are also available as process connectors.
Now the...connectors today really are designed to facilitate logic apps.
This talk is not a logic apps as a fantastic talk tomorrow
by steven and ilya and
...describe logic apps and show all kinds of amazing things because that's what they do but,
I'm going to show a little bit of it because I do want to demonstrate that.
The api apps that you build can also play in
...ecosystem of logic apps so you can build api apps
that then get because the because the fact that we're using swagger and swagger toyou can end
up using them as part of these logic apps that you build so,
let me go ahead and just show some of these things and action wrongs place.
So, again, for the sake a time when I did is ...deployed a few of these api apps I
had of time so thatwe could use them
...show you the experience here if you go new web plus mobile.
And, then as your marketplace
you can come here there's a lot of different things available measure marketplace if you select as
your api apps...see our of pretty much all the different connectors that
are available so you can select one of these connectors decide to create.
And, in some cases...can deploying right away
in other cases you may have to provide some credentials are keys or something that helps
...delineates you from other consumers of that...provider...when you don't it's
...typically because logic apps are using their own
are credentials to facilitate some of the consent and, authorization pieces with that
sas provider so I mean I'll go ahead and...create justthe fact that it will create will take
a couple minutes but what you'll see here is I already have a tool
eo connector and ar twitter connector so what I'm going to do is
especially for the sake of time...coming here to our web...mobile...create a logic app?
...called will demo and created now the thing to note is make sure that you create your logic
app in the same resource group is the api apps you want to use so that you have access to them.
And, this creates we're going to try to...very quickly since...have a few minutes left is
creates logic app that will ...from twitter
...keyword and then send...message so very simple demonstration but,
hopefully we'll reinforce you know, the capabilities
and ways in which you can use connectors measure api apps within the platform.
So, all right good usually doesn't take very long to
...a logic...so let's go ahead and open this up now I'm going to select
twittersince it has a built-in triggers...can actually.
Pole for different keyword so authorize it and that
is authorizing micro initials and we'll say look for new tweets not
...wagner notice I put to...signs in there that's because at is a special character
so we're skipping it save that and then I'm going to add julio so you probably
...I'm going with this...any of you have a twitter account you can participate so I'm
going-to send message now one of the things that's nice is with swagger we can detect
the outputs of one connector and use them as inputs and other so I
can say text and I can say tweet text and then here let's see.
I have my truly ode number I can pieced in here and then
yes this is my actual numbers so you can all call me and tell me how well I did.
All right so with that I'm going to save it.
All right my phone here somewhere.
So, now go ahead and run it now and at some point if someone ends
up tweaking anything with my name...I can see steve's on
...maybe he's helping out the demo but at any rate this workflow should start
running and presumably any time the twitter connector
...something...wagner it will end up sitting in sms message so
without the...my messages so...there's a quota so
generate hopefully this will start doing but that should demonstrate at least how
digesting here comes?
demonstrates how you can use connectors as part of building...logic gaps.
Right so to wrap it up I'm going to turn the sound off moi.
All right so.
In summary you know, one of these things you know, the measure api apps providing a number
of benefits here ways to make it easier for you to authenticate and authorize users
in the platform the metadata alone I think is very compelling in terms of
consuming interacting with these api apps the
on premises connectivity is fantastic I promise you and then being
able to create connectors and participate in these logic apps I think is also
a very compelling thing now a couple things that I want to mention things that are coming
in the hopefully in the near future but things that we are working on today we have a public gallery but,
for you to get your api apps...the public gallery you need to be working with us manually so we are
...you one of the things that...be bringing very soon is self-service
on boarding into our public gallery so just as we have new...and you can create
new packages and upload those new get packages and everyone can benefit from
in the near future you'll be able to create your own...api apps package them up
and submit them into a public gallery where people can then go in deploy
and instantiate your as your api apps so watch for that we're also going to be
bringing private organizational galleries in the future so that if you're
in enterprising have a bunch of ip and you want to make it very easy so that you can deploy and update
...manage are those as...api apps you'll be able to put a
package them up and put them in a private organizational gallery we are bringing
modernization the...the...as well and I moment I'm going to give you a link
to a user voice form where we'd love your feedback we want to know how you want to monetize are as
your api apps we fully intend to give you the ability to create some compelling as
your api apps put them into
the community and find ways in which you can make some money on them and,
then lastly and I put this here because a lot of the questions that we get our will how do what
what's the story between as your api management and measure api apps it seems like there's a lot
of overlap in two-degree there is...one of the things that you're going to see in the near future is these
two technologies converging, converging rather and a lot of the capabilities of the
as your api manned api management coming to as
...apps and vice versa so they'll be a lot of better together scenarios with those
two technologies and with that here are some of these resources where you can learn more there's a bunch
of fantastic documentation we'd love to get your feedback it's a very active user voice
forum and, there's also a form where you can ask questions if you get blocked of course
for those of you that participated in the logic app you already have my twitter
...name but there is if you want to reach me on twitter of course my email address as well and
thank you guys very much I'm going-to go ahead and load this thank you.